You pop your eyes in.
You reset your nervous system.
Would it be correct in saying that this is
the most expensive rehab in the world?
I would say that's probably the truest
thing.
You're coming here as an addict, extremely
vulnerable.
Helps with the circulation.
This creates more energy.
It's the diagnostic and the treatment.
Bioresonance tests which have no
scientific backing.
I just don't know how you could do it.
How are you feeling?
I actually felt that the money was killing
me.
It was very lonely.
If you carry on, you will develop a habit.
You know what you're feeling now?
Paracelsus is the world's most expensive
rehab and it costs I think 300 grand.
No, not 300 grand.
God, how much was it?
300 grand a month.
It costs 300 grand a month.
There is a luxury apartment, 24-hour
live-in therapist, psychiatric assessment,
addiction assessment, brain
analysis.
All these people around this table will be
discussing me.
I don't know if they're going to find that
I'm basically...
broken human being.
Growing up in central London, a lot of
people were working in the media.
It's become quite normalised, the drinking
and the casual drug taking.
Paracelsus is completely different to what
I've seen previously.
I've tried cognitive behavioural therapy.
I did AA for a while, where it's all about
group therapy.
This is like a one-on-one therapy session.
I'm very keen to get there.
Sydney, so nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Thanks so much for having me.
Now that I'm on my way to spend a free
weekend at the world's most expensive
rehab, I can find out whether money really
can solve all problems.
Oh, this is great.
I love it.
Do you play piano?
No, I can't.
This is the therapy room.
Ooh.
How are you?
You OK?
Yeah, I'm good.
How are you doing?
It's a bit crazy when you arrive.
Yeah, it is.
Yeah, a bit kind of nerve-wracking.
Oh, it's beautiful.
How do you feel now?
I feel fine.
It's obviously a strange set-up.
Yeah.
All right.
Bye.
He lives in this penthouse apartment.
and he doesn't leave.
How are you feeling, ma'am?
They're hungry.
Let's see if Magda prepared a nice juice.
Please, great.
Thank you so much.
It was really weird walking into a room
and having a team of people waiting on me.
I kind of just wanted to run and hide.
We do, in a way, create a kind of symbolic
family.
So Michael's like mummy and I can be a bit
like daddy.
Magic and cook.
Mission.
Eating with a stranger is awkward enough
without them also being paid to analyse
you.
I've got a charity for saving drowning
fish.
After some strange small talk, I was
straight into my first therapy session.
Start from the beginning.
My cancer separated when I was about seven
years old.
I lived with my mum and then I just
remember being very worried at school.
I started drinking when I was 13.
So you began drinking alcohol at 13?
Yeah.
I was terrified of drugs for ages and then
I just went a bit madder.
So then I wasn't scared of pills suddenly
and then I was like taking it, I wasn't
really scared of many drugs.
From like 17 to 21, I was just constantly
pissed or like...
On a com...
I just was delusional.
What?
I'm just wondering about your relationship
with your dad, that's all.
I've come to terms with being accepting,
but obviously I haven't.
Have I?
You tell me, Um...
I don't know.
So you were using coke up until last year?
I still do a bit of coke now and then.
Does it help you?
No, it makes you feel shit.
Why do you do it then?
Because if I'm pissed, I'll do a little
line.
Do you want to stop?
Yeah.
I find it really hard because it's so
normalised amongst everyone.
I just think you've got to maybe try to
stay away from things that currently don't
really help you.
Next on my programme is a session of
something called biochemical restoration,
which uses bioresonance technology.
Dr Riddell, Sydney.
This would be to test my intolerances.
In order to temporarily change my diet.
Whoa So this is really not so good.
This is the buckwheat.
You're allergic.
I was holding a rod.
My finger was tapped into something.
I was very bemused with what was going on
at the time.
You are allergic against the herring.
You're allergic against salmon.
I just had some Duck feathers.
Similarly with the Metatron.
They were scanning my body and then they
were finding the bits that weren't right
within my body and then downloading some
sort of
treatment to my body via a computer.
If I see your lymph node has not enough
energy, I can give him energy.
What?
It's the diagnostic and the treatment.
So you just click a button?
Computer is creating.
There is more.
So?
More.
There is something behind.
You're right.
It's in behind.
I had never experienced or heard of
anything like these tests.
And this is 100% gold and it helps to quit
the allergies.
Oh wow.
I mean, I'd just been given a solid gold
sticker to heal my previously unknown
herring and duck feather allergies.
I love herring.
When does it start kind of working?
Oh, it starts immediately.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So far, the main things that set
Paracelsus apart from other elite rehabs
The strange body assessments and the 24-7
live-in
therapist, Louis.
I wanted to find out more about where
these novel approaches came from, so I met
with the company's founder.
What do you get for that price tag that
other places can't provide?
Many things.
So what's the thinking behind the live-in
therapist?
It's basically something we invented.
If you have one client at a time, the
person cannot stay alone.
How do your clients receive that?
Initially it can be annoying, but I
think...
all of them very quickly come to really
appreciate the role and the person of the
live-in therapist.
Stuff like bioresonance, how does it work?
To be honest, I was quite skeptical
initially when we started working with it
because to understand the mechanisms is
immensely complex and it's
not something that you can tie directly
back to what's taught in medical school
today.
We never rely fully on it.
We always double check with the labs, but
with bioresonance we can really start
immediately with the right treatment
applications.
I'm just going to Google a few things
around bioresonance tests.
Small dessert.
Oh, thank you so much.
So enjoy.
Thank you.
And then we can have a rest after that.
Bioresonance, electrodermal testing.
There is little or no scientific rationale
for these methods.
I just feel like when you're in a
desperate position, as an addict coming
here, you will take
these bioresonance tests.
And not question them.
When maybe you should.
Hello?
Oh, Magda.
Yes, sir.
Oh, great.
Yes, sir, please.
That's your room.
This is my room.
Mm-hm.
If at any time during the night you need
to talk, just come and get me.
It's 6.30am and I'm being taken to the
Dolder Grand, which is the off-site spa.
for the Paracelsus.
It's probably the most luxury spa I've
ever been to.
It would definitely work for the 300 grand
a month as I mean you've got everything
here.
It definitely keeps up with a certain
standard of living, which I'm sure
everyone's used to.
I'm not used to hot stone baths.
I'm now trying to relax.
OK, I don't know if I can
do that.
Fucking hell I can't do it Ah Ah Fuck Fuck
Fuck.
OK, can I come out?
Oh, fuck.
I've got frostbite.
This does feel like the antidote to
unhealthy sex living.
but also what you might use to refresh and
get right back on it the next day.
I'm hoping Louis is not going to take me
aside at breakfast.
It's getting quite intense having him.
Any five minutes spare you have in between
testing, Louis is there
wanting to have a chat about how you feel.
And quite frankly now, I just don't feel
up for chatting.
Louis How are you?
I feel fine.
So how are you really?
What do you want me to say for how I am?
I mean, I'm fine.
Like, there's not much more I can...
Um...
Just in time for the next meal, a
dietitian arrives to tell Magda the 1,000
things I now supposedly can't eat.
Fish, I know, is struck off quite a lot,
but there were still a few things left
here which would be ideal for you.
I don't know if you're big on shellfish.
Not really.
In addition, so food-wise, lots of fruits
were taken off.
A lot of nuts were taken away, but
ultimately, variety is key.
How does the way you manage your diet...
Help overcoming substance abuse problems.
It wouldn't help you overcome a substance
abuse, but it would help with the person's
mood.
Thank you so much.
Even though Magda's food is pretty good,
my mood is just not improving.
No using the phone.
Pardon?
It felt more intense today.
Yeah, I did nearly tell Louis to fuck off.
I love Louis, but I just don't know how
you could do it every day.
I just feel a bit claustrophobic and
completely surrounded by people I don't
really know.
You know, you can't go out for walks.
I don't like it.
Hello.
This is intermittent hypoxic therapy.
We do cycles of low oxygen.
This creates more energy.
It's just a lot of really good effects.
Would it have any effect on, like...
Cravings.
Some people do experience less of an
appetite.
But what about cravings for alcohol?
Cravings for alcohol?
I have not heard that.
No.
I'm beginning to feel sceptical about how
any of these treatments and lifestyle
changes are really going to help overcome
any real issues.
Does it help addicts?
I wouldn't do cupping for addiction
treatments.
Then I would do acupuncture.
I'm just like shooting in my back.
I didn't know if I was being a massive
cynic.
or whether all of this was actually a bit
daft.
You pop your eyes in.
Yes.
Oh.
Oh, yes.
Now what?
You reset your nervous system.
Resetting your nervous system?
I've never heard that one before.
It's in my eye.
But maybe when you're paying this absurd
price, you need a parade of novelties to
either keep you occupied or feel as though
you're getting your money's
worth.
Kidney, I'm fine.
Your liver is fine.
Great.
In order to show me just how effective
their treatment actually is, Paracelsus
have organised for me to meet a former
client.
Paracelsus, it was for me the most
important decision I have made in my life.
What were your issues?
Well, I had mainly alcohol and cocaine.
Most of the people I know who have those
type of issues, they don't want to be in
any group sessions.
They're concerned about reputation.
No one in my life, on my circle, even
noticed that I was in treatment.
How much were you spending on your drug
habit and drink habit?
There was no problem to spend 50,000 in
the night or more.
People who live this type of lifestyle,
they also spend a lot of money on inviting
other people.
I was really able to party for three days
and go to work like nothing happened.
Can you describe what your life was like
when you were at your lowest point during
addiction?
The last time I chatted, I had from Cannes
to Sardinia.
I remember that at some point I was
throwing up overboard and people were
lying there and they
were all messed up and I didn't even
remember where they came from.
It was very lonely.
My life was going too fast to nowhere.
I looked at the Mediterranean Sea and
there was a beautiful
sunrise and I felt like you've got to
change something.
And is that when you came to Paracelsus?
After that, yes.
So I stayed, I think, for two months and
then I came back and used
Paracelsus as my support system.
And how much did you spend in total?
It was like 800, 200 million, yeah.
Can you give us a rough idea of how
wealthy you are?
Well, I don't know what I would say.
It would be enough to stay for the rest of
my life at Paracelsus.
It's easy to see how Paracelsus could
become a temporary escape for people whose
lives at the mortuary have no budgetary
limits.
People of that power, money can keep them
going for a long time.
So the rock bottom is when they end up in
the emergency room.
or sometimes in a morgue.
It's hard for the average population to
really have empathy for somebody who has
it all, who can afford everything, to
actually be
allowed to.
suffer and have problems.
At some point that kind of lifestyle
becomes a bit dull.
Boredom is a big factor when you have a
lot of wealth and really no purpose.
You need a reason to get out of bed in the
morning and that's not just to go to the
next party.
That purpose doesn't last very long.
That really isolates and in the end it's
that loneliness and the pain that comes
from that loneliness and often also
associated boredom
that leads to this pain and inner void
that the people start to self-medicate.
You know, you were seven years old and you
probably were fully aware of the tension
between your mum and dad.
And then the anxiety kicks in, just
letting it all go and drugs and crazy and
that just made it
worse.
It never went away.
Do you know what you're feeling now?
It's quite intense, isn't it?
Of course.
I think we're talking about your dad.
I think that's what's going on.
Do you want us to leave?
Yeah, alright.
Thanks.
If you carry on with that acceptance of
it's London and it's part of the scene,
I'm just going to do it,
that process of engaging may increase and
then you will
develop a habit.
The idea of abstinence is that when you're
trying to rewrite neural pathways is the
way to go.
You're giving yourself every opportunity
to create new experience and it's a new
experience which challenges the
neuroplasticity
which then creates the change in the
brain.
The sheer quantity of treatments on offer
at Paracelsus can often feel like a way to
justify the price tag.
But the main focus is therapy and if it
eventually forced me to engage with my
issues it can do the same for the 1%.
As much as we love to pile in on rich
people, I guess wealth can sometimes be a
gilded cage that leads to isolation.
But for those of us who can't hire a team
of people to make us feel better whenever
we want, a church hall and a few chairs
are just as good.
And there's probably a reason it's unusual
for therapists to sit with you for all
your meals and refer to themselves as your
symbolic dad.
I'm excited to get back.
I'm excited to have a glass of wine.
I probably shouldn't say that.